{
    "id": "7a33ffe11030402e891c1b073ae12f37",
    "title": "Present Perfect Or Simple Past Tense Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "ed98b3c4c1fd468ab2358c507701f435",
            "title": "Present Perfect Or Simple Past Tense Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "She ...................... to anybody in her life.",
                    "description": "The present perfect is more common with time expressions like ever, never, yet, before and already.",
                    "answers": [
                        "never apologized",
                        "has never apologized",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I am sure we ……………… before.",
                    "description": "The present perfect is more common with time expressions like ever, never, yet, before and already.",
                    "answers": [
                        "never met",
                        "have never met",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ……………. a word with the manager in the morning.",
                    "description": "The present perfect is not used to talk about a finished event if we say when it happened.",
                    "answers": [
                        "had",
                        "have had",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ………….. two movies yesterday.",
                    "description": "The present perfect is not used to talk about a finished event if we say when it happened.",
                    "answers": [
                        "watched",
                        "have watched",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "How long ………………….. in love with him?",
                    "description": "The present perfect is used to talk about how long present situations have lasted.",
                    "answers": [
                        "were you",
                        "have you been",
                        "are you"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "She …………… at thirty-nine.",
                    "description": "The present perfect is not used to talk about a finished event if we say when it happened. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "died",
                        "dead",
                        "has died"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The number of unemployed ……………….. ten million.",
                    "description": "The present perfect is the most normal tense for giving news of recent events.",
                    "answers": [
                        "reached",
                        "has reached",
                        "had reached"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "………………….. the people who live next door?",
                    "description": "The present perfect is more common with the indefinite time expressions ever, never, yet, already.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Did you ever meet",
                        "Have you ever met",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The Defense Minister …………… a meeting with the Prime Minister yesterday.",
                    "description": "We do not use the present perfect tense with past time expressions. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "had",
                        "has had",
                        "had had"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "During the two hour meeting, they ……………. the economic situation.",
                    "description": "The present perfect is not used when the reference is to the past time. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "discussed",
                        "have discussed",
                        "had discussed"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "We …………….. that you have homes to let.",
                    "description": "Sometimes past and present perfect are both possible.",
                    "answers": [
                        "heard",
                        "have heard",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who …………….. the telephone?",
                    "description": "We use the simple past when we ask about the person responsible for a present situation.",
                    "answers": [
                        "invented",
                        "has invented",
                        "had invented"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}